RODRIGO THAUBY

Engineering Manager

rthauby@gmail.com

www.thauby.com

(717) 802-4802

ABOUT ME

I am an experienced Engineering Manager with a background in client-side code, user experience and games/interactive content. I have deep knowledge of all stages of the Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC) from planning, through development, to deployment on the cloud.

Core Skills

People management Relationship building Communication Team building

Stakeholder management Hands-on leadership Problem solving

EXPERIENCE

Engineering Manager (Growth), Evernote, Remote

October 2019 - February 2023

- Managed a team of 5 engineers and was responsible for their mentorship, growth, performance evaluation and job satisfaction.
- Created and maintained client health monitoring via DataDog for Growth Zone.
- Proven record of recruiting, developing, and retaining talent.
- Fostered a culture of ownership to improve processes, resulting in improved productivity and 3 IC promotions.
- Collaborated with Product in creating detailed Roadmaps resulting in increasingly accurate forecasting and scheduling.
- Delivered well-architected, well-documented, high quality results at a fast pace.

UI Engineer, Virtru, Washington D.C.

August 2017 - March 2019

- Worked closely with project managers, stakeholders and designers to bring new features to existing products.
- Designed and developed new Front End standards for use across teams, resulting in increased design consistency and fewer bugs.
- Designed and maintained various tools to help facilitate the UX team and Front End pipeline.
- Designed, developed, and integrated new UI components in React to be embedded into existing applications.

UI Developer, Sparkypants Studios, Baltimore MD

February 2017 - June 2017 (Company closed)

- Jumped into a fast paced team-environment with a unique approach to software development/deployment, and successfully adapted quickly to it.
- Helped concieve new UI elements and systems for new gameplay and saw them through to execution.
- Designed new features in Photoshop, and built them using Web Technologies (HTML/CSS/JS) and integrated them into a native client application.

EXPERIENCE (CONT)

Senior Developer, ISL, Washington D.C.

July 2013 - February 2017

- Worked closely with clients, project managers and designers under tight deadlines to deliver high quality, high interactivity marketing products.
- Single-handedly created the company's first VR prototype, as a proof of concept.
- Mentored apprentices and junior developers into the Front End technologies and techniques used at ISL.
- Founded and hosted the Game Development guild where engineers and nonengineers could learn the ins and outs of Unity and Unreal Engine dev.

Senior Software Engineer, SocialCode, Washington D.C.

April 2012 - July 2013

- Worked closely with product designer and project manager to determine market needs and schedule feature rollout.
- Built main product "Message Optics" prototype in Backbone. JS with communications via websockets to a django-based backend.
- Streamlined css styles generation via modular pattern (BEM) Built features in agile environment and participated in scrum meetings daily

Software Engineer, Forio Business Simulations, San Francisco CA

July 2008 - April 2012

- Designed and developed interface for main online product "Simulate" and conducted several usability tests and refinements.
- Designed and developed interfaces for multiple simulation projects for Universities including Harvard, MIT and The Wharton School of Business.
- Successfully completed project management for each simulation, scheduling iteration meetings with clients, refining the product and coordinating user tests.
- Developed interfaces for simulations in HTML (Velocity), Javascript (JQuery and YUI) and some projects in Flex.
- Developed numerous tools for testing, including some automation tools for XMPPbased chat and bots for simulation testing.
- Developed tests for the Selenium IDE for Firefox.

EDUCATION

MS Web Engineering

University of San Francisco 2011 BS Industrial Eng.

Universidad Adolfo Ibañez, Chile 2005